Nichole Johnson

3310 East Tucker Drive Northwest Huntsville, AL 35810

+1 205 285 3625

nichole.iohnson0530@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nichole-johnson-77099b263/

https://flutterdev6778-mobile.webflow.io/projects

I'm a successful software developer offering 10 years of experience in demanding environments focused on producing cutting-edge systems in a variety of domains and tech stacks. My strongest skills are Node.js, TypeScript, Vuejs, Reactjs, Go/Golang, Flutter, Microservices and Docker for rapid development and scaling. I have significant experience working in startups and fast-moving teams with fixed deadlines. Quickly learns and masters new technologies while working in both teams and self-directed settings.

Skills

- 1. Javascript(8), Typescript(5), VueJs(5), Vuex(5), Nuxtjs(3), Nextjs(7), ReactJs(8), Redux(5), Html(8), CSS3(8), SCSS(7), JQuery(8), Json(7), XML(4),
- 2. Flutter(5), Dart(5), React Native(5)
- 3. NodeJs(7), Python(4), Django(4), Numpy(3), matplotlib(3), Go(5), GraphQL(5), PostgreSQL(5), Java(1), Spring boot(1)
- 4. AWS(4), Google Cloud Platform(5), Azure(1), Docker(4), Microservices(5), Git(8), Agile Methodology/Jira(5)

Experience

Feb 2021 - Jan 2023 · San Francisco, CA, USA

GitStart - Software Engineer/Tech leader(*contract/remote*)

- Led four (4) software engineers in delivery of web scraping engine project, resulting in well-collected data for further analysis. Delegating tasks in weekly sprints and running daily standups
- Worked closely with Product Client and teammate to build a generic web scraper to scrap any Ecommerce site to get product details stack. Tech used are Go,Go-colly and PostgreSQL
- Delivered Nium's Banking-as-a-Service (BaaS) Platform which is a flexible, comprehensive, and easy-to-embed fintech infrastructure platform with timeframes. Frameworks used are ReactNative, GraphQL, GO and deployed at AWS cloud services
- Worked with a software engineers team to deliver Sourcegraph fast and featureful code with optimized search and navigation engine. Framework use Go, TypeScript and deployed at AWS cloud services

Skills: React, React Native, GraphQL, Go, Amazon Web Services, PostgreSQL

Mar 2022 - Sep 2022 · San Francisco, California, United States

Phonon X, Inc - Flutter Developer(contract/remote)

- worked on a carbon voice flutter project with a team.
- Carbon Voice creates a better way to talk and share.
- The Carbon Voice platform handles the complexities of audio to enable a range of experiences for you to engage with your team, customers, and partners while on-the-go.
- Team Chat: A better way to talk & share with your on-the-go, distributed teams
- CarbonLink: Give your customers, partners, audience, and field teams a link to start a voice conversation with you.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.phononx.carbonvoice

https://carbonvoice.app/

Skills: Flutter, Getx, Bloc, GCP, Swagger, RESTful Api, Jira, Slack,

Jul 2021 - Nov 2021 · North Carolina, USA

Caring - Full-Stack Engineer(contract/remote)

- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.
- Worked on Provider and Contract Microservice. Frameworks used are Golang,
 GraphGL gateway, Docker, AWS, Reactjs, Gatsby and deployed at AWS cloud services

Skills: Docker, GatsbyJS, GraphQL, Go, Amazon Web Services (AWS), React.js, PostgreSQL

Jul 2020 - Jan 2021 Eagle, Idaho, United States

Blackwater Billing Services - Full Stack Engineer(contract/remote)

- We provide world-class billing services to Water Damage Restoration and Hazardous Material Remediation contractors.
- Blackwater's Cloud and Mobile tools for Contractors and Billing Companies enable your success and put you in control
- Blackwater handles every aspect of the billing process from dispatch to payment received. Use our software to enter job scope data and manage the technical work, or send us job scope data in the format of your choice. We take it from there. If you don't need a complete billing solution and just want help with one or two billing functions, give us a call. Our services are tailored to meet your needs.

Implemented Frontend using vue + nuxt.js and backend using spring boot. Using websocket, implemented synchronization of all the data.

https://www.blackwaterbilling.com/

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/10T6Nh1YZivEe4U2uLSJhgyogm7RokCb8

Skills: Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Spring boot, MySQL, AWS s3, AWS ec2, AWS cloudFront, websocket, Jira, Slack,

Feb 2020 - SEP 2020 · Hyderabad, India

TradeMantri - Full stack Developer (*remote*)

Our SAAS based online app brings digital benefits to all.

- Our app users can turn their physical store or service in to strong online footprint, catalogue, showcase & sell their products & services to wider audience.
- Businesses will increase their visibility, availability & top-line by selling online, retain old customers and add new ones. TM app offers contact less ordering and payment services.
- Business have end to end digital support like purchases, inventory and supplier payment management
- TM facilitates multiple businesses collaboration and connectivity. Businesses can connect
 with other businesses, retailers can connect to distributors and perform B2B ordering
 without broker's intervention.
- Retailers can ensure customer's safety and convenience, providing real time customer
 experience by utilizing the "check in" and "book appointment" feature which allows only
 selected people to enter the store and shop.
- Create excitement and opportunity for customers with never before buying experience through bargain tag, e-bids and reverse auction.
- Store representatives can resolve any kind of issues using our live chat platform.
- Enable businesses to post or announce all their business requirements, updates, latest offers to customers and other businesses.
- Businesses can configure reward points, coupons etc.

I built an e-commerce project and built 3 flutter mobile apps(customer, store, delivery apps) and 3 node backends and admin panel

https://www.linkedin.com/company/trademantri/

https://flutterdev6778-mobile.webflow.io/product/trademantri-customer

https://flutterdev6778-mobile.webflow.io/product/trademantri-business-store

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tradilligence.tradeMantriDeliveryApp

Skills: Flutter, Node.js, Vue, GCP, AWS lambda, s3, EC2, websocket,

Mar 2019 - Feb 2020 · Greater Lyon Area, French

Legatus - Full Stack Developer(*remote*)

APPLICATION AND SOFTWARE FOR THE STATEMENTS OF BAILIFFS / COMMISSIONERS OF JUSTICE

- Legatus offers Commissioners / Bailiffs a productivity solution to manage their findings, from making appointments to making them available to the applicant.
- Offer your employees and customers a simple and complete interface for the production of reports.

https://www.legatus.fr/

https://flutterdev6778-mobile.webflow.io/product/legatus

Skills: Flutter, Node.js, React.js, GCP, Swagger, Trello,...

Jan 2019 - May 2019 · Singapore

AREIX - Flutter Developer (remote)

- I built several beautiful UI and integrated with restful api.
- I built two parts of the Areix app, that is, the campaign and marketplace part.
- You can check all the screen images and xd design files which I built on google drive.

https://flutterdev6778-mobile.webflow.io/product/areix https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1I34ftpq4dEzy7H9_veLgLopU3v3S-RcU https://areix-ai.com/

Skills: Flutter, Good Flutter responsive UI design skill

Mar 2017 - Nov 2018 · Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria

OutSource Global Technologies - Software Engineer(*remote*)

- Created User interface of NASIMS using Reactjs, styled component and Typescript. This
 project includes Npower statistic, CCT and HGSF as of right now over 50 million individuals
 are benefiting from this project. Frameworks used are Reactjs, TypeScript and Redux toolkit
- Created procedures for system monitoring, recovery, backup and optimization.
- Implemented frontend(UI) of payroll app which enables OGTL to pay workers with ease, This solution increases company productivity by 74%. Payments are now met on a timely basis. Frameworks used are Vuex, Vuejs, HTML and SCSS.
- Automated and implemented backup and recovery procedures for Deploying pipeline.

Skills: Redux · Vue.js · Vuex · TypeScript · React.js

June 2016 - Jan 2017 · Calabar, Cross River State, Nigeria

Investlift Technology - Team leader/Software Engineer (remote)

- Promoted from developer to team lead and project manager to define corporate strategy based on business goals and strategic initiative developed creative and profitable solutions for internal/external clients.
- Oversees software platform design and custom software delivery for multi-million naira accounts.
- Defined and directed project goals, objectives, critical success factors, milestones and risks.
- Successfully taught seven IT students on Data visualization, Web design, Version control,
 Mobile Development using these programming languages: Python, JavaScript, Go, and Dart.
 Frameworks are React, Vuejs, Panda, Numpy, matplotlib, Flutter etc. 6 Students are now full
 employers in Investlift.
- Implemented successful E-commence website where users can buy and sell goods. Framework used are Reactjs, Nextjs for frontend and Go(Golang) ,go-micro(gRPC) for Backend, which are deploy digital ocean

Skills: Python, NumPy, Panda, Next.js, Vue.js, Go, Dart, Flutter, React.js, JavaScript, PostgreSQL

Nov 2013 - Mar 2015 · Jos, Plateau State, Nigeria

Interswitch Technology - Data Analyst(contract/remote)

- Teamed with engineers to manage customers' Database and consistent reliable learning systems by heavily making use of these tools MySQL and PostgreSQL which in turns increase customers satisfactory by 40%.
- Evaluated consistency and importance of different business intelligence data against needs to determine optimal courses of action. Making use of Python, Panda and Numpy.

Skills: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Python, NumPy, Panda

May 2014 - Current

Freelancer.com - Full Stack Developer(freelancer/remote/Part-time)

I built many web and mobile projects.

Education

Jan 2008 - Jul 2013

Federal University Of Technology Minna - Bachelor of Computer Science

Certifications

Wisdom Impact in Computer Training Certificate

Majored in Computer Programmer languages In Software Development

Majored in Project Management for Software Programmers.

System Administration for an E-Library Integrated and Designed School Database

Full-Stack With Node.js, Express, and MongoDB, of Open Classrooms - November 14, 2019